You don't want to live with a man like him, right?
妳不想跟這種人住一起吧？
-That man is no longer our father. -You pretentious bastard!
-他已經不是我們的爸爸了 -你這個虛偽的混蛋！
This is from Kii.
這是希衣給你的
Good morning.
早安
You should prepare to leave for work soon.
您應該趕快準備上班了
Right.
好
I guess you couldn't care less about what happened yesterday.
看來妳根本不在乎昨天發生的事吧
Mr. Asuda.
主人
Yes?
什麼事？
Can I clean up that area over there?
我可以清理那個區域嗎？
CREATING A TOWN TO PROTECT YOUR BELOVED FAMILY
（創造一個城鎮，守護最愛的家人）
Go ahead.
妳清吧
Wait…
等等
You have a call from Ms. Urara.
小麗小姐來電找你
Hello?
喂？
Keiichi?
姐夫？
You weren't picking up your phone, so I sent you a text.
你沒有接電話，所以我傳了簡訊給你
Did you read it?
你有看到嗎？
What?
什麼？
URARA: YUI AND THE KIDS ARE WITH ME DON'T WORRY
（結城麗：小結他們和我在一起 別擔心）
I see…
這樣啊
Just what happened?
發生什麼事了？
I've never heard of you guys quarreling before.
我從沒聽說過你們吵架
I was shocked.
我好驚訝
You didn't hear anything from the kids?
孩子們沒有提起嗎？
They just said they didn't want to be with you anymore.
他們只說不想再跟你一起住了
When I asked why,
我問起原因
they told me to ask you.
他們叫我問你
Is everything all right, Keiichi?
姐夫，一切還好嗎？
I'm a teacher,
我是老師
so you can rely on me at times like this.
你在這種時候可以仰賴我
No, it's nothing serious.
不，沒什麼
Keiichi?
姐夫？
What?
什麼事？
Urara…
小麗
Nagiko…
止子
Your older sister…
妳姐姐
She wasn't involved in an accident.
不是出意外
She committed suicide.
她是自殺的
What?
什麼？
I found someone I love,
我愛上了別人
and I asked her if we could get a divorce.
我問她能不能離婚
And the next day…
結果隔天…
I'm sorry.
對不起
You don't have to apologize to me.
你不用向我道歉
Sorry, I…
抱歉，我…
I'm a little surprised right now, so…
我現在有點吃驚，所以…
I'm sorry.
抱歉
For now,
目前
I'll keep it a secret from Dad.
我會先瞞著爸
He might end up killing you, Keiichi.
他可能會想殺了你，姐夫
I'm sorry.
對不起
Yui and the kids asked me to bring their luggage over,
小結他們請我帶他們的行李過來
Can I drop by the house after work today?
我今天下班後可以過去你家嗎？
Of course.
沒問題
See you later, then.
那就到時見了
You surprised me, Dad! What is it?
你嚇我一跳，爸，什麼事？
What did he say?
他說了什麼？
Keiichi was really stressed with work.
姐夫工作壓力很大
Yui and the kids wouldn't listen to him,
小結他們不聽他的話
so he got angry and shouted at them.
所以他就生氣罵人
He told them to get out.
叫他們出去
Is that really all?
真的只有這樣嗎？
That's right.
對
It's just the usual fight between parent and children,
只是普通的親子之間的吵架而已
so don't do anything unnecessary.
所以別做沒必要的事
This looks like a breakfast set from some luxurious inn.
看起來好像豪華飯店的早餐套餐
Thank you for the food.
我開動了
To be honest,
老實說
I prefer having a Japanese breakfast.
我比較愛吃日式早餐
But the kids prefer otherwise.
但孩子們喜歡吃別的
My late wife liked bread, too.
我過世的妻子也愛吃麵包
In usual cases,
一般來說
the parent would have gone to take back their children.
父母會去帶小孩回來
But…
但是…
I don't know what I should do.
我不知道該怎麼做
No matter what I say,
無論我說什麼
I'm not sure if they will forgive me.
也不知道他們會不會原諒我
I never wanted any children.
我一直不想生小孩
But I married anyway,
但還是結婚了
and got swept along this far.
就這樣一直過到現在
"I will protect my children with my life."
“我會和太太一輩子保護孩子
"I love my children
我打從心底
from the bottom of my heart."
深愛我的孩子”
I just couldn't say it
這話我說不出口
like I mean it.
無法真心地說
I'm sure
我相信
that I lack the parental love
我缺乏一般人對孩子擁有的
normal people have towards their own children.
父母的愛
I think you should hurry.
我認為您應該動作快一點
You will be late for work.
您上班會遲到的
Hey…
喂
Why don't you say
妳為什麼
how you feel once in a while?
不偶爾表達一下妳的感受？
Yesterday, you said you don't have a heart.
昨天妳說妳沒有心
But I'm sure you're human, too!
但我相信妳也是人
In the first place,
一開始
things turned into this huge mess
情況變得這麼糟
because you do everything that we ask!
就是因為妳完全照我們的話去做
Wait.
等等
Don't tell me that
難道說
you planned to destroy our family in the first place?
妳一開始就打算破壞我們的家庭？
Is that it?
是這樣嗎？
What time will you return today?
您今天幾點回家？
What should I prepare for dinner?
我晚餐要準備什麼菜？
Enough already!
夠了
The kids are not here. You don't need to work anymore!
孩子不在，妳不需要再工作了
I'll contact the agency!
我會聯絡介紹所
As you wish.
好的
This is the spare key,
這是備用鑰匙
and the remaining grocery allowance.
和剩下的雜貨零用金
Also, the invoice for my work so far.
還有我目前為止工作的收據
Thanks.
謝謝
Mr. Asuda.
主人
Yes?
什麼事？
It was short,
雖然很短暫
but thank you for everything.
但是謝謝你的照顧
Hey.
喂
What should we do, Yui?
姐，我們該怎麼做？
Are we going to stay with them from now on?
我們接下來要跟他們住嗎？
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
Urara's cooking is bad,
小麗煮的菜很難吃
and Grandpa is annoying.
外公又很煩
I know, but still…
我知道，可是…
I… I want to go home.
我…我想回家
I want to see Daddy!
我想見爸爸
Didn't I tell you?
不是告訴過妳了嗎？
That man tried to abandon us to marry some other woman!
那個人想拋棄我們去娶別的女人
Mom died because of that!
媽媽因為這樣死了
I will never forgive him!
我永遠不會原諒他的
I'll never acknowledge him as our father!
我永遠不會認他這個爸爸
Then are you going to sever your relationship with Dad?
那你要斷絕跟爸的關係嗎？
Of course!
當然了
Hey, what does it mean to "sever your relationship"?
“斷絕關係”是什麼意思？
It means we will never meet that man, ever, even if we die.
意思是我們到死 都不會再見到那個人
Then what about our school and living expenses?
那我們的學費和生活費怎麼辦？
Are we going to ask Grandpa and Urara to pay for us?
要請外公和小麗幫我們付嗎？
I still want to attend a private school, you know.
我還想上私立學校
That's…
這…
Damn it, aren't you mad?
可惡，你不生氣嗎？
Your real father did something like that!
親生的爸爸做出那種事
I'm just trying to work out our practical problems.
我只是想解決實際的問題
I… I want to go home!
我…我想回家
I want to go home!
我想回家
Don't ask for the impossible, Kii.
別要求不可能的事，希衣
Why don't you say something, Yui?
妳說話啊，姐
For now,
目前
we have no choice but to stay with Grandpa.
我們不得不跟外公住
In the meantime,
同時
all of us have to think about what to do.
我們都要想想該怎麼辦
We have the right to request child support from that man.
我們有權利向那個人要求撫養費
For now? Until when?
目前？要到什麼時候？
We'll have to think about that, too.
這我們也得想想
Come on, Kii. I'll take you to school today.
來，希衣，今天我帶妳去上學
What about going home? Will Mita come fetch me?
回家怎麼辦？三田小姐會來接我嗎？
No.
不會
Mita has nothing to do with us anymore.
三田小姐跟我們沒有關係了
Then I'll go home alone!
那我得自己回家
I can't allow that.
我不會允許的
What if you get abducted?
萬一妳被綁架怎麼辦？
What's abducted?
什麼是綁架？
It means that a bad person might take you to a strange place,
意思是壞人可能會帶妳去奇怪的地方
and kill you.
把妳殺掉
If that happens, our family will be very sad.
要是這樣的話，家裡的人會很難過的
Due to some circumstances,
因為某些原因
I'm no longer in charge of this project.
我不再負責這個專案
From now on,
從現在起
do your best with Natori.
請和名取一起努力
I will support everyone behind the scenes, too.
我也會在幕後支持大家的
It's a shame.
真可惜
I'm so incompetent compared to you, Chief.
跟你相比我的能力不足，課長
What are you saying? That's not true.
你在說什麼呀？才不是這樣
Well then.
那就這樣了
That's the person Kazama is involved with?
風間就是跟那個人在一起的嗎？
He's the one having an affair with Kazama?
跟風間有婚外情的就是他？
INCOMING CALL MIE KAZAMA
（風間美枝來電）
Hello?
喂？
Is it true that they're transferring you to the model house exhibition?
你要被調到樣品屋展示部是真的嗎？
I caused such a huge commotion after all.
畢竟我造成這麼大的騷動
Keiichi Asuda has been having an affair with Mie Kazama since last year.
阿須田惠一從去年起 就跟風間美枝有婚外情
Hey…
是說…
Could we meet after work today?
今天下班後可以見面嗎？
What?
什麼？
Just a while will do.
一下下就好
I'm begging you.
拜託
I can't.
不行
You're the only one I have now.
我現在只有妳了
Don't leave me alone.
別拋下我
Even when I'm home,
就算在家裡
I feel like my wife's photo is condemning me.
我也覺得我太太的照片在譴責我
I'm in a relationship with someone else.
我現在和別人交往了
What?
什麼？
So please forget about me.
請忘了我吧
Wait a minute…
等一下…
You left home? Then what will you do now?
妳離開家裡了？那妳要怎麼辦？
None of us like staying at our grandfather's house
沒有人喜歡住在外公家
and we can't survive without our father's financial support.
我們也不能沒有爸爸財務上的支援
But I will never forgive him.
但我永遠不會原諒他的
Jeez…
唉…
Why do I have to deal with such things?
為什麼我要面對這種事？
Cheer up!
振作起來
I'll do anything I can to help.
我會盡力幫忙的
Right. Why don't you stay over again?
那妳要不要再來我家過夜？
Oh, I can't today.
今天不行
I can't leave my siblings alone.
我不能丟下弟弟妹妹不管
Right.
好
Yes.
是的
Excuse me.
不好意思
I received a university recommendation,
我收到了大學推薦入學通知
and my classmates wouldn't stop bugging me about it.
我同學一直在煩我這件事
Hello?
喂？
Come on, it's nothing.
拜託，這又沒什麼
Why don't you attend my university next year?
你明年可以來念我的大學，不是嗎？
MISAWA KINDERGARTEN
（三澤幼稚園）
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kii. Let's go.
希衣，抱歉讓妳久等了，走吧
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I want to go home!
我想回家
What?
什麼？
I don't like Grandpa's house!
我不喜歡外公家
I want to go home!
我想回家
Well…
這…
But if you do that, Yui and Kakeru will be angry.
要是妳這麼做，姐姐和哥哥會生氣的
Then I'll go meet Mita.
那我要去找三田小姐
I'll ask Mita to help us!
我要請三田小姐幫忙
Well…
這…
But…
但是…
Let's go together, Kai!
小斗，我們一起去
I heard you kids left home.
聽說你們離家出走了
I feel so sorry.
真替你們難過
Just what happened with your father?
你們跟爸爸發生什麼事了？
If you're troubled by anything,
如果遇到什麼問題
I'll hear you out.
我願意聽你們說
No thanks.
不用了，謝謝
We're going to see Mita now.
我們現在要去找三田小姐
That housekeeper is fired, you know.
那個家政婦已經被解僱了
But I'm relieved
不過我鬆了一口氣
that a dangerous person like her is gone.
像她那麼危險的人離開了
-Shall we go home, Tsubasa? -Yes.
-我們回家吧，小翼 -好
I'll make you your favorite omelet rice today!
今天我要做你最愛吃的蛋包飯
All right!
好耶
Can I have meat, too?
我可以吃肉嗎？
What should we do, Kai?
小斗，我們該怎麼辦？
Hey!
啊
There she is!
她在那裡
Mita!
三田小姐
Why are you two here?
你們兩個怎麼在這裡？
Oh, we just happened to see you here.
我們剛好看到妳在這裡
What are you doing here?
妳在這裡做什麼？
Are you waiting for someone?
妳在等人嗎？
No.
沒有
Then,
那麼
why did you buy extra French fries and cola?
妳為什麼多買一份薯條跟可樂？
You're not eating them at all.
妳又沒在吃
That is because…
這是因為…
I want to.
我想要這麼做
Please, Mita!
三田小姐，拜託妳
Help Daddy, Yui and Kakeru make up.
幫忙讓爸爸和哥哥姐姐和好
I want to live in that house with everyone together again.
我想再次跟大家一起住在那個家裡
I'm sorry, but I cannot do that.
抱歉，我不能這麼做
Why?
為什麼？
I have been fired,
我被解僱了
and I am no longer related to you.
跟你們沒有關係了
Then I'll pay you!
那我付錢給妳
How much do we need to hire you?
僱用妳要花多少錢？
Four thousand yen for a minimum duration of two hours.
四千日圓，至少工作兩小時
The recommendation fee costs 520 yen,
還有介紹費是520日圓
so it will be 4,520 yen in total.
所以一共是4520日圓
We don't have that much money!
我們沒有那麼多錢
Please excuse me.
失陪了
Mita!
三田小姐
PERSONNEL TRANSFER NOTICE KEIICHI ASUDA
（轉職通知，阿須田惠一）
I'll take the children's belongings with me, Keiichi.
姐夫，我把孩子們的東西帶走囉
Sorry to cause you trouble, Urara.
抱歉給妳帶來麻煩了，小麗
It's fine.
沒關係
But what will you do now?
但你現在要怎麼辦？
I told Dad that it's just the usual fight.
我告訴爸只是普通的吵架而已
This can't go on forever.
不能一直這樣下去
What do you think I should do, Urara?
小麗，妳覺得我該怎麼辦？
What?
什麼？
How will the children forgive
孩子們要如何原諒
a father who caused their mother to commit suicide?
造成媽媽自殺的爸爸？
I think…
我認為…
You have to talk to them.
你得和他們談談
"I'm your father!"
“我是你們的爸爸
"I love all of you the most in this entire world!"
全世界我最愛的就是你們”
It will be fine as long as you express your feelings to them!
只要你向他們表達感受就會沒事了
In the first place,
一開始
Nagiko didn't have to abandon the kids
姐姐不需要只因為你有外遇
and kill herself just because you had an affair!
就拋棄小孩去自殺
I also lost my mother around the same age Yui did,
我大約在小結這年紀時也失去了媽媽
so I understand how tough it is for a child to lose their mother.
所以我明白失去媽媽的孩子有多難受
I don't mind looking after them in place of their mother, you know?
我不介意代替媽媽照顧他們的
I didn't mean it in a strange way, but…
我沒有別的意思啦，只是…
Hey, Urara.
小麗啊
Why are you such a nice person?
妳為什麼這麼善良？
What?
什麼？
I mean,
我是說
you always say there's no bad person in this world,
妳總是說世界上沒有壞人
and that you can get by as long as you have love and smiles.
只要有愛與笑容就能過下去
Humans aren't such simplistic beings.
人不是這麼簡單的
I can't believe you're a teacher. Don't your students make fun of you?
真不敢相信妳是老師 妳的學生沒取笑過妳嗎？
Well…
這…
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
I'm spouting nonsense because I'm tired.
我累了，所以亂說話
I'll take you home.
我送妳回去吧
-Near your house, that is. -It's fine, Keiichi! Bye!
-送到妳家附近 -沒關係的，姐夫，再見
Wait, Urara.
等等，小麗
Urara?
小麗？
Your father looked really down.
你們的爸爸看起來很沮喪
I understand how you guys feel, but why don't you forgive him already?
我明白你們的感受 但你們可以原諒他了吧？
You only have one father in this world!
你們在世界上只有一個爸爸
You see, Nagiko was already married by the time Mom passed away,
我媽媽過世的時候，姐姐已經出嫁了
so I've been living alone with Dad since then.
所以在那之後，一直只有我跟我爸住
He nags at me every single day.
他每天都對我嘮叨
I don't think that I want to see his face,
我真的不想再看到他的臉了
-but… -Did you say something?
-但是… -妳說了什麼嗎？
Nothing. Why don't you go take a bath, Dad?
沒事，爸，你要不要去洗澡？
I'm about to.
我現在要去
You guys should go sleep soon, too.
你們也該早點睡了
Got it!
好
Urara.
小麗
What is it?
什麼事？
Our mom…
我們的媽媽…
Why did she marry that man?
為什麼和那個人結婚？
Well…
這…
That's because she has been in love with Keiichi for a long time.
這是因為她愛著姐夫很久了
And she was pregnant with you, Yui.
而且她懷了妳，小結
Then I shouldn't have been born.
那我不該出生的
What are you saying? Of course that's not true!
妳在說什麼啊？當然不是這樣
Sorry, but I have studying to do.
抱歉，我得去念書
Let's play another round, Yui.
我們再玩一輪嘛，小結
Hey…
等等
Wait. I still need to talk to you, Kakeru.
等一下，我還有話要跟你說，小翔
I only went along because you had to take our belongings.
我只是因為 妳得幫我們拿行李才陪妳的
Cut me some slack.
放過我吧
-Me, too, then. -What?
-那我也要走 -什麼？
Don't say that too, Kaito.
不要你也這樣嘛，小斗
You keep drawing the old maid no matter how many rounds we play, Urara.
小麗，不管我們玩多少輪 每次都是妳抽到老女傭
I have a favor to ask, Urara.
小麗，我想請妳幫個忙
What is it, Kii? Just say it.
希衣，什麼事？妳儘管說
Could you lend me money?
可以借我錢嗎？
You want to hire Akari?
妳想僱用燈子？
Yes.
對
How long can I hire Mita with this amount of money?
這筆錢可以僱用三田多久？
Let's see…
我看看
A total of 7,600 yen.
一共7600日圓
Let's see… Give me a moment.
我看看…等我一下
-Five hours. -Right.
-五小時 -對
Seven thousand five hundred yen gives me five hours!
7600日圓可以僱用五小時
Wait…
等等
I'm sorry,
對不起
but you also need to pay a referral commission of 975 yen.
但妳還要付975日圓的介紹費
What? Please give me a discount.
什麼？請給我優惠
You say that, but this old lady here needs to make a living as well.
話是這麼說 但我這個老婆婆也要生活啊
Please!
拜託
Besides, if I sign a contract with a young girl like you,
而且，要是我跟妳這麼小的女孩簽約
it's not right according to the law.
法律上是不對的
-Not right? -Well…
-不對？ -是啊
It's just not right.
就是不對
This is giving me a headache.
這樣讓我好頭痛
You surprised me!
嚇我一跳
Could you please stop doing that?
妳可以不要再這樣了嗎？
You know, sometimes you appear out of nowhere like a ninja.
有時候妳會像忍者一樣突然冒出來
It's bad for my heart!
對我的心臟不好
My apologies.
真抱歉
What is this urgent matter?
有什麼急事？
This girl says that she wants to hire you.
這個女孩說想僱用妳
For four hours, that is.
四個小時
Make it five!
五個小時吧
Please, Mita!
拜託妳，三田小姐
What do you say?
妳說呢？
I don't mind.
我不介意
So…
那麼…
What am I supposed to do?
我要做什麼？
Help Daddy, Yui and Kakeru make up!
幫忙讓爸爸和哥哥姐姐和好
I told you before,
我告訴過妳了
that is impossible.
這是不可能的
Why?
為什麼？
Only family members
只有家人
can help each other reconcile.
才能幫助彼此和好
I thought about it.
我想過了
In order for us to make up,
為了讓我們和好
we need to meet.
我們必須見面
But I don't know what to do
但我不知道要怎麼樣
to make that happen.
才能做到
There is a simple method
有個簡單的方法
to make a separated family come together.
能讓破碎的家庭團結
What is it?
是什麼方法？
It's when someone gets into an accident,
就是當有人發生意外
or falls seriously ill.
或是生重病時
Otherwise,
否則
people will not gather out of concern.
大家不會出於關心集合在一起
Then I'll get sick!
那我就生病吧
It's easy to find out if someone is pretending to be sick.
假裝生病是很容易被發現的
Then I'll get into an accident.
那我發生意外好了
It will be very painful.
那會很痛苦的
Are you fine with that?
妳沒關係嗎？
Then what should I do?
那我該怎麼做？
That is…
這是…
something you should decide for yourself.
妳應該自己決定的事
I got it.
我想到了
I have a request.
我有個要求
Please take your time.
（澤井建設樣品屋展示地點）
-This way. -I want a huge room like that, Daddy!
-這邊請 -爸爸，我想要那麼大的房間
Okay, in the future.
好啊，有一天會的
DO YOU LIKE ME, DADDY? I LOVE YOU, DADDY!
（爸爸，你愛我嗎？ 希衣最愛你了）
MITA
（三田來電）
Hello?
喂？
I'm Mita, the housekeeper.
我是家政婦三田
Do you need anything?
有什麼事嗎？
I abducted Kii.
我綁架了希衣
What?
什麼？
If you want her back,
要是你想要她回去
you have to agree to my terms.
就要同意我的條件
Just hold on a minute.
等一下
If you do not comply,
要是你不合作
I cannot guarantee Kii's safety.
我不能擔保希衣的安全
Do you know what you're saying?
妳知道自己在說什麼嗎？
Besides, you're not even working for our family anymore.
而且妳已經不再為我們家工作了
I'm currently being hired by Kii.
目前是希衣僱用我
Wait.
等等
Then did Kii tell you to kidnap her?
那是希衣叫妳綁架她的嗎？
Kii has a message for you.
希衣有個訊息要給你
What?
什麼？
"I want to live in the house with everyone together again."
“我想再跟大家一起住在家裡
"If we can't do that, I will die."
如果不行的話，我就會死”
What's that?
什麼啊？
I relayed the same message to Yui and the other kids.
我把相同的訊息傳達給 小結和其他孩子了
So call me back on this phone
等到你們準備好接受我的條件
once you are ready to accept my conditions.
就用這支電話回電給我吧
Wait a minute! I…
等一下…
Seriously, just what is that housekeeper thinking?
真是的，那個家政婦在想什麼？
Hey! What should we do, Yui?
姐，我們該怎麼做？
For now,
我們就暫時
just pretend to make up with Dad…
假裝跟爸和好吧
I will never do that!
我才不要！
MITA
（三田）
Hello.
喂？
Hello, Mita?
喂？三田小姐嗎？
Could you let Kii use the phone?
可以讓希衣來講電話嗎？
I'm sorry,
很抱歉
but can you have Mr. Asuda call
如果有任何要求
if you need anything from me?
可以請妳叫阿須田先生打給我嗎？
Wait! Hello?
等等！喂？
Just what's going on?
到底怎麼回事啊？
What did she say?
她說什麼？
She said she will only take Dad's calls.
她說她只接爸的電話
Then what do we do?
那我們該怎麼辦？
We don't have a choice.
我們別無選擇
For now, let's go look for her.
目前先去找她吧
-Right! -Hey!
-好 -喂
Where are you guys going?
你們要去哪裡？
What? Oh… We need to do something.
什麼？這…我們有事
Where's Kii?
希衣呢？
I haven't seen her today.
我今天都沒看到她
-What? -Kii is hanging out at her friend's place.
-什麼？ -希衣去朋友家玩了
-We're going to fetch her now. -Right! We'll be back soon.
-我們現在要去接她 -對，我們馬上回來
Dear me…
真是的
What?
什麼啊？
Akari abducted someone now?
燈子綁架人了？
I'm sorry, but could you tell us Mita's home address?
很抱歉，可以請妳告訴我們 三田家的地址嗎？
Well, I'm sorry.
很抱歉
The thing is…
但是…
I have that thing to keep.
我得遵守那個
-The duty to confidentiality? -This isn't the time for that!
-保密義務？ -現在不是說這個的時候
Hey, could you not be so angry?
你們可以不要這麼生氣嗎？
Have some monaka. Here you go.
吃點最中餅吧，來
We don't need these!
我們不要吃
What?
什麼？
I'll tell you, then.
那我告訴你們吧
Akari's home address is…
燈子的住址是…
She doesn't have one.
她沒有住址
-What?
-什麼？
What?
什麼？
What do you mean by that?
妳這是什麼意思？
Well…
這…
You see,
其實
she does have a residential address written here.
這裡的確寫著一個住址
But I also don't know where she lives.
但我也不知道她住哪裡
Wait.
等等
You kids can't tell anyone about this, okay?
你們這些孩子 不能告訴任何人，好嗎？
It's going to be bad if the town office knows about this.
要是鎮上的官員知道這件事就糟了
-So don't do that. -No way…
-別這麼做 -不會吧…
Then we have no choice but to call the police, Yui.
姐，那我們別無選擇，只能報警了
I don't think it's a good idea.
我覺得那樣不好
I don't think Mita would really kill Kii.
我認為三田小姐不會真的殺了希衣
Are you siding with that housekeeper?
你站在那個家政婦那邊嗎？
-Stop getting so uptight about everything! -You guys…
-不要什麼事都這麼緊張好嗎？ -你們…
No fighting among siblings!
兄弟姐妹不要吵架
Oh, so you guys came here, too.
你們也來這裡了啊
Did you all also come here to ask about Mita's home address?
你們也是來問三田小姐的住址嗎？
-Okay, let's go find Kii. -Where?
-好，我們去找希衣吧 -去哪裡找？
I mean, there's the amusement park!
可以去遊樂園
-I think it's already closed for the day. -What?
-那裡今天已經關閉了 -什麼？
It could be that place!
可能是那裡
That place?
那裡？
The river where Mom died.
媽媽死掉的那條河
Hey! I have a car. Get in!
喂，我有車，上車啊
Hello, Urara?
喂？小麗嗎？
Hey, wait up!
喂，等等
Sorry, Urara. Did you need anything?
抱歉，小麗，有什麼事嗎？
We're having barbecue today. Why don't you come over?
今天要烤肉，你要不要過來？
Don't worry!
別擔心
Someone bad at cooking like me will never mess up a barbecue!
就算是我這麼不會煮菜的人 也絕對不會搞砸烤肉的
Oh!
唉呀
Sorry, Urara. But I'm busy now!
抱歉，小麗，我現在在忙
Yesterday, Kii asked if she could borrow money from me.
昨天希衣問我能不能借錢給她
I thought about what she could be using it for,
我在想她會拿來做什麼
but I'm sure she's getting presents for everyone--
但我相信她是用來買禮物給大家…
URARA YUKI
（結城麗）
-Kii! -Kii?
-希衣
The other side!
另一邊
-Is Kii here? -Did Mita call you?
-希衣在這裡嗎？ -三田小姐有打給你嗎？
No, not yet.
沒有，還沒
I knew it.
我就知道
We just need to agree to Kii's condition and make up.
我們只要同意希衣的條件 和好就可以了
There's no way we can do that!
這是不可能的
We were betrayed by this person!
我們被這個人背叛了
Then what will we tell Mita?
那我們要怎麼告訴三田小姐？
Everyone…
你們…
Won't you return to the house?
你們不回家嗎？
We also need to resolve this incident.
我們得解決這件事
I'm begging everyone!
拜託你們
I don't care if you blame everything on me.
我不介意你們把事情全怪在我頭上
Okay?
好嗎？
All right.
好
So I'll call Mita now.
那我現在打給三田小姐
Do you really want that?
你真的想要嗎？
-What? -Do you want to live with us?
-什麼？ -你想和我們一起生活嗎？
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼？
Of course I want to.
我當然想了
Didn't you tell us before?
你不是告訴過我們嗎？
You said you weren't sure
你說你不確定
if you really loved Mom.
是不是真的愛媽
That's, well…
那是…
Do you…
你…
really love us?
真的愛我們嗎？
Of course I do.
當然愛了
More than your mistress?
比對你的情婦更愛嗎？
Can you say we're more important to you than that person?
你能說我們比那個人更重要嗎？
This is where Mom died.
這裡是媽死的地方
Don't you dare lie.
不准說謊
Well, I…
我…
It's from Mita.
是三田小姐打來的
Put it on speaker mode, so we can all hear her.
開擴音模式讓大家都能聽到
Hello?
喂？
Kii is asking if you will comply with her condition.
希衣問你們會不會照她的條件去做
Tell Kii to stop this ridiculous joke!
告訴希衣停止這個荒唐的玩笑
Please give me a moment.
請等一下
Kii says, "I hate you, Yui!"
希衣說“我討厭姐姐”
Tell Kii that everyone is worried about her!
告訴希衣大家都在擔心她
Kii says, "You're annoying, Kakeru, so shut up!"
希衣說“小翔你很煩，閉嘴”
Then ask Kii this.
那妳問希衣
She said she's going to die, but how is she going to do it?
她說她會死，但她要怎麼死？
She says, "I will set the house on fire."
她說“我會放火燒房子”
I see.
我懂了
What?
什麼？
Hey, where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
Don't you get it?
你們不懂嗎？
Kii said that she's going to set the house on fire!
希衣說她要放火燒房子啊
-Hey! -Right!
-啊 -對耶
-Kii!
-希衣
-You guys found her?
-你們找到她了嗎？
Mita!
三田小姐
Where is Kii?
希衣在哪裡？
-I cannot answer you. -What's up with that?
-我不能回答妳 -妳是怎麼回事啊？
I'll go search the second floor!
我去二樓找
-Kii! -Hey!
-希衣 -喂
Kii!
希衣
Maybe she's not here after all.
也許她不在這裡
Hey…
啊
Over there!
那邊
Wait.
等等
What are you doing, Kii?
希衣，妳在做什麼？
Don't come over!
不要過來
It's dangerous there, Kii. Get off!
希衣，那邊很危險，快下來
Has everyone made up?
大家都和好了嗎？
Didn't I tell you
我不是告訴你們
that I'll die if you don't make up?
如果不和好，我就會死？
Don't be ridiculous!
別鬧了
-If you come over, I'll jump down! -Hey!
-要是你們過來，我就跳下去 -喂
Don't keep quiet.
別靜靜站在那裡
Say something. You're the father!
說話呀，你是爸爸
Kii.
希衣
Go down from there and we'll talk, okay?
下來吧，我們談談，好嗎？
No!
不要
I'll go meet Mommy!
我要去見媽媽
Don't say that!
不要這麼說
Come on, take my hand!
快抓住我的手
No!
不要
Wait,
等等
what are you guys doing?
你們在做什麼？
-Kii!
-希衣
Ouch…
好痛啊
That hurt!
真痛
Daddy.
爸爸
Don't you ever do that again!
不准再這麼做了
Do you know how worried everyone was?
妳知道大家有多擔心嗎？
I'm sorry…
對不起
You dropped this.
妳掉了這個
No!
糟糕
One of the stones I gave Mom is missing!
我給媽媽的石頭，有一顆不見了
Kii?
希衣？
It's just one stone. I'll get you a new one.
只是一顆石頭而已 我再給妳一顆新的就好
No! That stone represents Daddy!
不行，那顆石頭代表爸爸
What?
什麼？
This is Mommy,
這是媽媽
this is Yui,
這是姐姐
this is Kakeru,
這是小翔
and this is Kai.
這是小斗
And this is me!
這是我
So Daddy has to be here, too!
所以爸爸一定要在才行
Mita.
三田小姐
Do you have a flashlight?
妳有手電筒嗎？
I do.
有的
Thanks.
謝謝
Excuse me.
借過
I'll help you, too, Kii!
我也來幫妳，希衣
-Here, I found it! -This one.
-我找到了… -這個
-That's not it! -Oh, sorry.
-不是這個 -對不起…
I found it this time, Kii!
這次我找到了，希衣
-No! This isn't it either! -What?
-也不是這個 -什麼？
Oh, wait!
等等
What about this, Kii?
希衣，那這個呢？
No!
不對
Stop it, Kii!
希衣，夠了
We don't have a father!
我們沒有爸爸
Why are you saying that, Yui?
姐姐，妳為什麼這麼說？
Just forgive Daddy!
原諒爸爸吧
Kakeru.
小翔
My kindergarten teacher told me
我的幼稚園老師告訴我
that if we fight with someone,
如果跟別人吵架
we must make up with them.
一定要跟對方和好
Kai.
小斗
Let's live with Daddy again!
我們回來跟爸爸一起住吧
Daddy.
爸爸
Did you read my letter?
你有讀我的信嗎？
Yes.
有
DO YOU LIKE ME, DADDY? I LOVE YOU, DADDY!
（爸爸，你愛我嗎？ 希衣最愛你了）
I love you, Daddy.
我愛你，爸爸
Do you love me, Daddy?
爸爸，你愛我嗎？
I don't know.
我不知道
Hey.
喂
What's with that answer?
這是什麼回答？
I'm sorry.
對不起
That is this man's true nature!
這就是這個人真正的本性
You kids were acting strange,
你的小孩舉止很奇怪
so I thought something is up.
我想應該有事發生了
And this is what happened?
結果是這種事？
Grandpa!
外公
How could you look at my belongings without my permission?
你怎麼可以擅自看我的東西？
You.
你
Come with me.
跟我來
What is this?
這是做什麼？
You did this
你這麼做
because you're scared of seeing Nagiko, right?
是因為你害怕看到止子，對吧？
-You bastard! -Hey! Stop it, Dad!
-你這個混帳！ -住手，爸！
Stay out of this!
妳別管
Why did my daughter have to die because of someone like you?
為什麼我女兒要為了你這種人死？
Why is Nagiko dead, and you're still alive?
為什麼止子死了，你卻還活著？
You should have just died!
你應該死的！
If you can't kill yourself,
要是你不能自殺
I'll do it for you.
我就代替你下手
Wait.
等等
Stop this, Dad!
住手，爸
-Stop it! -Yui!
-住手 -姐姐
Dad!
爸
-Dad! -Grandpa!
-爸 -外公
-Stop it, Grandpa! -Stop!
-住手，外公… -住手
I will raise these kids
我會代替止子
in Nagiko's place.
撫養這些孩子
I will never hand them to you again!
我永遠不會把他們交給你的
Okay, everyone. Let's go back.
好了，大家，我們回去吧
Come on.
走吧
Hey.
喂
What are you all doing?
你們在做什麼？
Hurry up!
快點
Come on, let's go.
快走吧
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
對不起，外公
We'll stay in this house.
我們要留在這個家裡
-You'll forgive this man? -That's not it.
-妳要原諒這個人？ -不是這樣
But this is our home.
但這裡是我們的家
We can't have Kii trying something like this again.
我們不能讓希衣再嘗試這種事
Could you leave this house instead?
可以換你離開這個家嗎？
It's all your fault, anyway.
畢竟這都是你的錯
Isn't this the least you could do for us?
你至少能為我們這麼做吧？
I'll take care of…
我會照顧…
my siblings.
我的弟弟妹妹
Mita!
三田小姐
I'm sorry,
對不起
but my contract with you has expired.
我和妳的合約期限已經過了
Mita.
三田小姐
Sorry to trouble you,
很抱歉帶給妳麻煩
but could you work for the kids in this house again?
可以請妳回來這個家 為這些孩子工作嗎？
I'll contact the agency about this.
我會跟介紹所聯絡
As you wish.
好的
I will never acknowledge this man!
我永遠不會承認這個人
Let's just go home already, Dad!
我們回去了，爸
-Why don't you say something, too? -I…
-妳為什麼沒說話？ -我…
I'm on their side.
我也站在他們那邊
Just stop this already!
夠了啦
Let's go home, Dad!
我們回去了，爸
Come on!
快點
Mita…
三田小姐
I'm leaving the kids to you.
我把孩子們交給妳了
Understood.
我知道了
See you, everyone.
再見了，大家
The kids
孩子們
are finally sick of me.
終於厭倦我了
Well,
看來
I guess I deserved it.
這是我活該
I've never hit anyone before,
我從來沒打過人
but I did that to Kii.
我卻打了希衣
As a father,
身為爸爸
I should have given her a hug.
我應該抱抱她才對
When a child does something wrong,
當小孩做錯事時
it is a given that you reprimand them.
責備是應該的
What?
什麼？
It's something you should do…
這是你身為父親
as a father.
應該做的事
It's not normal for children to live with just their housekeeper.
小孩只跟家政婦住在一起是不正常的
You do everything we ask?
妳會完全照我們的話去做？
This is an order.
這是命令
Could you turn this house upside down?
妳可以把這棟房子顛倒過來嗎？
As you wish.
好的
What are you doing, Mita?
三田小姐，妳在做什麼？
THIS DRAMA IS FICTIONAL.
（本故事純屬虛構）
What should I do to nurture parental love?
我該怎麼做才能培養父愛？
Dad is planning to adopt the kids.
爸打算領養孩子們
Are you running away, you coward?
懦夫，你要逃跑嗎？
Tell me what you think.
告訴我妳的想法
You must have your own thoughts.
妳一定有自己的想法
I have a question for everyone.
我有個問題要問大家